Mss.Rec.163 Mss.Rec.163
American Philosophical Society
Recordings of Nisgha language field studies
1989-1990
Mss.Rec.163
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings in Vancover, British Columbia in August and September 1989, and in New Aiyansh, British Columbia in August 1990. Nisgha language elicitations, word lists, and grammar; narratives about the Nisgha and Gitksan, and the flooding of Old Aiyansh; free translations of Psalm 23 and the Lord's Prayer into Nisgha; brief Christian hymn sung in Nisgha.
5 sound tape reels (1 hr., 42 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in.
Azak, Bertha
Azak, Joshua
Belvin, Robert S.
Doolan, Dorothy
Grandison, Pauline
Haizimsque, Sam
Haizimsque, Sarah
Robinson, Rosie
Williams, Verna
Related Archival Materials
Project report available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Arrangement note
Reels originally numbered 1, 2A, 2B, 3A, 3B. Contents of tape 5 (3B) are identical to tape 3 (2B) despite different labelling.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Robert Belvin in 1990 (Acc. 1991-409ms). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Gitksan Indians; Indians of North America--British Columbia; Niska Indians; Niska Indians--History; Niska language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-24; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:12; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Niska language; Vancouver (B.C.)
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-25; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-28; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:58; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-29; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:04; Belvin, Robert S.; Doolan, Dorothy
    Anthropological linguistics; Niska language; Niska language--Grammar; Vancouver (B.C.)
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-29; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:21; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-30; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:42; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-08-31; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:02; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1989-09-01; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:26; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-07; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:34; Belvin, Robert S.; Grandison, Pauline
    Anthropological linguistics; New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska language; Niska language--Grammar
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-07; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; Azak, Bertha; Azak, Joshua; Belvin, Robert S.
    New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska language
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-09; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:10; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sam
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-12; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:01; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sam
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-13; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:52; Belvin, Robert S.; Robinson, Rosie; Williams, Verna
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-15; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:52; Belvin, Robert S.; Robinson, Rosie; Williams, Verna
  - Nisgha elicitation session, 1990-08-16; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:58; Azak, Bertha; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sam; Haizimsque, Sarah
  - Free translation of Psalm 23, 1990-08-10; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:31; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sam
    Anthropological linguistics; Bible. O.T. Psalms XXIII; New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska language
  - Third verse of "When I Survey the Wondrous Cross" in Nisgha, 1990-08-10; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sarah
    Anthropological linguistics; Hymns; New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska language
  - Free translation of the Lord's Prayer, 1990-08-10; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sam
    Anthropological linguistics; Lord's Prayer; New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska language
  - The Flooding of Old Aiyansh, 1990-08-15; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:05; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sarah
    Aiyansh (B.C.)--History; Anthropological linguistics; Floods--British Columbia; New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska Indians--History; Niska language
  - Narration of Andy Capp Cartoon, 1990-08-07; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:47; Belvin, Robert S.; Grandison, Pauline
    Anthropological linguistics; Capp, Andy (Fictitious character); New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska language
  - The Nisgha and Gitksan, 1990-08-13; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:41; Belvin, Robert S.; Haizimsque, Sam
    Anthropological linguistics; Gitksan Indians; Indians of North America--British Columbia; New Aiyansh (B.C.); Niska Indians; Niska language